{
    "id": "f52592d027d247aa963e3834baa89d78",
    "title": "Grammar Exercise (Gap Filling)",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Sam ......................... James has agreed to come.",
            "description": "When we connect two singular subjects with as well as, the verb is singular in number. ",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "as well",
                "as well as"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a83af4b60c084ca5a408e60ad5e32eaa"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… being rich and famous, she is very humble.",
            "description": "Despite is a preposition. It should be followed by a noun or ing form. ",
            "answers": [
                "Though",
                "However",
                "Despite"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "96eb10f6129f4a8293555a6acaddddbd"
        },
        {
            "question": "We played to the best of our ability …………………….., we could not win.",
            "description": "However does not connect two sentences. It is a transitional adverb. Put a full stop or a semicolon before however. ",
            "answers": [
                "though",
                "however",
                "despite"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "26a49ade1b6248848db624fc857bc06f"
        },
        {
            "question": "You should not marry ……………………….. you are financially independent.",
            "description": "Either could be used here with slightly different meanings. ",
            "answers": [
                "until",
                "unless",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "2e5275acdf0d4fe7b7df7dae5c88a2f0"
        },
        {
            "question": "You must work ……………………. starve.",
            "description": "Or is used to give the alternative. ",
            "answers": [
                "and",
                "but",
                "or"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4876d758352a451aafa784a734a7ce78"
        },
        {
            "question": "She ought to get the job ……………………….. she is the most suitable candidate.",
            "description": "For is possible here is a more formal style. ",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "because",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "5a918bc6ff8843abb925a04bf1bb38a4"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………… he is not educated, he is industrious.",
            "description": "Though is used to connect two contrasting ideas. ",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "Though",
                "If"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d88bf3cf504641d3b8ef8e558cf80105"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. it was a hot day, I felt lethargic.",
            "description": "For cannot begin a sentence. ",
            "answers": [
                "As",
                "For",
                "Since"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d76b8b0f50ca46088c36abcd58334dfa"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………. you are free tomorrow, let’s catch up over a coffee.",
            "description": "If expresses a condition. ",
            "answers": [
                "If",
                "Whether",
                "Unless"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e31b5a46f8684c1891f028f3663fc9b7"
        },
        {
            "question": "I wasn’t feeling well, …………………….. I called in sick.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "hence",
                "so",
                "because"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e031b345e544437691a9d2651abf46d3"
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the park ………………………. we used to meet.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "there",
                "where",
                "here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "26af39e0cd184c529fbe9ae476458107"
        },
        {
            "question": "It hasn’t rained …………………….. months.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "for",
                "in",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "2524b747b3264fd89d306353b98cb834"
        }
    ]
}